startingstrength.com 2019-09-07

# Starting Strength

## Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, and shared when you visit startingstrength.com (the “Site”). 

## Information Collected

We collect three basic types of information from you in conjunction with your use of the Site: (1) personal information, which is any information that individually identifies you (e.g., your name, email address, physical location), (2) non-personal information, which is information that does not personally identify you but may include information about your use of the Site, and (3) device information, including information about your web browser, IP address, and time zone.

### We collect this information in the following ways:

#### Information You Provide Directly To Us When You:

  * Register for an account on the Site
  * Sign up to receive email newsletters from us
  * Enter a contest or sweepstakes
  * Participate in surveys or special promotions
  * Knowingly volunteer information on any other part of the Site (e.g., request for customer service, post to the public forum)

#### Information Collected Using Technology:

When you visit the Site, we automatically collect certain information about your device, including information about your web browser, IP address, and time zone. Additionally, as you browse the Site, we collect information about the individual web pages or products that you view, what websites or search terms referred you to the Site, and information about how you interact with the Site. We refer to this automatically-collected information as “Device Information.”

We collect Device Information using the following technologies:

  * “Cookies” are data files that are placed on your device or computer and often include an anonymous unique identifier. For more information about cookies, and how to disable cookies, visit allaboutcookies.org.
  * “Log files” track actions occurring on the Site, and collect data including your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, and date/time stamps.

## Use of Your Personal Information

We use the Information that we collect generally to maintain your forum account on the Site. Additionally, we may use this Information to:

  * Communicate with you
  * Screen for potential risk or fraud

We use the Device Information that we collect to help us screen for potential risk and fraud (in particular, your IP address), and more generally to improve and optimize our Site (for example, by generating analytics about how our customers browse and interact with the Site, and to assess the success of our marketing and advertising campaigns).

## Sharing Your Personal Information

We share your Personal Information with third parties to help us use your Personal Information, as described above.

Subscribing to the Starting Strength Weekly Report creates an account with Mailchimp for purposes of the weekly mailing. Mailchimp tracks how you interact with the mailing, including tracking of opens and clicks. You may unsubscribe from this service at any time. Please contact us to request that any listing of your unsubscribed account is fully removed from Mailchimp's system.

We also use Google Analytics to help us understand how you use the Site. You can read more about how Google uses your Personal Information here: [google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](https://policies.google.com/privacy "Google Privacy Policy"). You can also opt-out of Google Analytics using this tool: [tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout "Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on").

We use the “visitor action pixels” from Facebook on our website. This allows user behavior to be tracked after they have been redirected to the provider’s website by clicking on a Facebook ad. This enables us to measure the effectiveness of Facebook ads for statistical and market research purposes. The data collected in this way is anonymous to us, but this data is stored and processed by Facebook, which is why we are informing you, based on our knowledge of the situation. Facebook may link this information to your Facebook account and also use it for its own promotional purposes, in accordance with [Facebook’s Data Usage Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/ "Facebook Data Usage Policy"). You can allow Facebook and its partners to place ads on and off Facebook. A cookie may also be stored on your computer for these purposes. You can object to the collection of your data by Facebook pixel, or to the use of your data for the purpose of displaying Facebook ads by contacting the following address: [Facebook Ads](https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads "Facebook Ads").

Finally, we may also share your Personal Information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful request for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights.

## Your Control of Your Personal Data

You may access personal information we hold about you and to ask that your personal information be corrected, updated, or deleted. If you would like to do this, please contact us through the contact information below.

## Data Retention

Accounts on the Starting Strength Forums, https://startingstrength.com/resources/forum, are retained to preserve the utility of the public forum and for purposes of security and minimization of abuse.

European Users: When you create an account on our Forum, we will maintain your account until and unless you ask us to delete personal information associated with the account. Posts you have submitted will be retained. Personal information you have posted will be removed when specific posts containing such information are identified to us with a request that that specific information be redacted.

Other Users: You may make a special request for your account to be converted to an anonymous account by contacting us below.

## Updates

We may update this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons.

## Contact Us

If you have questions about this privacy policy, please contact us by email at [stef@startingstrength.com](mailto:stef@startingstrength.com).
